and outside this office there were steps
that actually led up to the second floor
which is where the office was and the
windows in the office were those windows
that you you know you roll outwards so
they didn't open up and down they opened
outward and I thought man this is Wow I
have a window that opens outward and the
steps going up right up right underneath
it this this is kind of like dangerous I
would always tell the girls don't play
with these windows don't open them up
because you could get hurt someone
coming up these stairs you know may
unexpectedly run into this window
because they're not looking up and you
know my girls would do it they'd say
okay daddy and then guess what they'd
opened the windows and I would tell them
time after time
don't open that I've seen open guys
don't open the windows someone could get
hurt did they listen
no it's fast forward a few months it's
prayer meeting night and I'm getting
ready to go to prayer meeting and I
forgot something in the office it's dark
outside so I take off because you know I
got to get to prayer meeting and so I'm
like oh man forgot the thing in the
office so off I go running as fast as I
can as fast as I can and and when I get
to the steps you know I'm a pretty tall
person so I'm not going to the steps one
by one
I am leaping like a roll just sleeping
like a deer leaping for steps at a time
five steps like a sprinter like a you
know just boom I'm in it because I'm not
good you know I'm and after about my
fourth leap as I'm leaping all I see is
the edge of something coming towards my
eye and if any of you ever seen this
scar right above my eyebrow you now know
where it is from because that the edge
of that window basically Gow
majd now one of my daughter's was
running behind me she was a little
distance away but she was running behind
me and when I jumped into the port the
edge of the window I let out a scream
that I don't think that they will ever
forget blood I'm sorry
empathy I'm looking at your faces right
now and I'm seeing empathy you are
acting like you yourself or I'm on the
ground screaming in pain like screaming
in pain I think that I have lost an eye
and and I'm Todd like by the grace of
God the thing totally missed my eye
it went from my eyebrow down the side of
my face and I am screaming now now
listen to where I'm going with this
my daughters were right there they
watched it they watched their father
lying on the ground in pain blood on the
ground I know I'm painting a picture I
know I know but I need you to get I need
you to empathize with what I'm saying
right now because let me tell you this
is like we got it going
I'm gonna come back to that I want you
to remember your response i'ma build on
that okay listen my daughter's after
they saw that after that experience
guess what that window remained closed
for the rest of the time that we lived
there they never touched the window
again okay when we see what our
disobedience caused someone do you know
what happens someone that we love see
they can tell us how don't do this don't
do this don't do this don't and we're
like ok whatever what ok when we
understand what our iniquities what our
sins does to someone else that we love
when we truly see what it does when we
see it and let me tell you something it
may have been different if the if my
kids weren't out there but the fact that
they saw that it was enough that I never
had to say again don't open the window I
didn't have to say it you want to know
why because they had an experience I
mean II believe they had an experience
how many of you believe that it was as
if their I had been as in their face I
mean they saw it and when you see when
your close up at the ringside when your
close up where the action is something
happens that is different than when you
just hear about it or read about it are
you with me
when we as a people see I want you to
imagine God in the garden hey guys don't
eat that tree don't eat from that tree
because somebody could get hurt don't
eat from that tree guys because you
could get hurt somebody could get hurt
and when Adam and Eve ate from that tree
little did they realize that they were
bringing about the death of their
creator when we understand when we see
what sin does it changes us it changes
us